let natureOfMatter = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: `A small quantity of solid ammonium chloride ${formula(
      "NH",
      4,
      "Cl"
    )}was heated gently in a test-tube, the solid gradually disappeared to produce a mixture of two gases. Later a white cloudy deposit was observed on the cooler part of the test tube. The ammonium chloride is said to have undergone`,
    options: [`distillation`, `sublimation`, `precipitation`, `evaporation`],
    ans: "B",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: `Which of the following changes is physical?`,
    options: [
      `adding iron fillings to aerated water`,
      `cooling a solution of iron(II) sulphate to obtain the hydrated salt`,
      `cooling water to obtain ice`,
      `adding sodium metal to water`,
      `burning domestic gas`,
    ],
    ans: "C",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: `By means of filtration one compound can be obtained pure from an aqueous mixture of sodium chloride and`,
    options: [
      `potassium nitrate`,
      `sand`,
      `lead nitrate`,
      `sugar(glucose)`,
      `starch`,
    ],
    ans: "B",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: `Methanoic acid mixes with water in all proportions and has the same boiling point as water. Which of the following methods would you adopt to obtain pure water from sand and methanoic acid`,
    options: [
      `fractional distillation`,
      `filtration followed by distillation`,
      `neutralization with sodium hydroxide followed by distillation`,
      `neutralization with sodium hydroxide followed by filtration`,
      `esterification with ethanol followed by distillation`,
    ],
    ans: "B",
    // not yet solved
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: `One of the following techniques can be used to show that chlorophyll pigments is a mixture of chemical compounds and not a single compound`,
    options: [
      `crystallization`,
      `hydrolysis`,
      `sublimation`,
      `filtration`,
      `chromatography`,
    ],
    ans: "E",
    // not yet solved
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: `In an attempt to remove sugar from a beaker containing a quantity of sand and sugar, 2M ammonium chloride solution was accidentally added instead of water. Which of the following methods could be used to remove ammonium chloride from the mixture.`,
    options: [
      `fractional distillation`,
      `crystallization`,
      `filtration followed by sublimation`,
      `evaporation followed by sublimation`,
      `filtration followed by sublimation`,
    ],
    ans: "E",
    // not yet solved
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: `Which of the following compounds and elements would sublime on exposure to the atmosphere`,
    options: [
      `ice`,
      `sulphur`,
      `phosphorus`,
      `iodine`,
      `potassium iodide`,
    ],
    ans: "D",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: `Which of the following process does NOT lead to chemical change.`,
    options: [
      `stirring iron in sulphur(VI) acid`,
      `stirring sodium carbonate in water`,
      `stirring glucose in conc. Sulphuric acid`,
      `mixing sulphuric acid with potassium carbonate`,
      `titrating an acid against a base`,
    ],
    ans: "B",
    remark: "B is just adding salt to water which produces nothing new."
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: `A mixture of common salt, ammonium chloride and barium sulphate can best be separated by`,
    options: [
      `addition of water followed by filtration then sublimation`,
      `addition of water followed by sublimation then filtration`,
      `sublimation followed by addition of water then filtration`,
      `mixing sulphuric acid with potassium carbonate`,
      `fractional crystallization`,
    ],
    ans: "C",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: `Sodium chloride may be obtained from brine by`,
    options: [
      `titration`,
      `decantation`,
      `evaporation`,
      `sublimation`,
      `distillation`,
    ],
    ans: "C",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: `In an experiment, which of the following observation would suggest that a solid sample is a mixture? The`,
    options: [
      `solid can be ground to a fine powder`,
      `density of the solid is 2.25 g/dm3`,
      `solid begins to melt at 573K but is not completely melted until 648K`,
      `solid absorbs moisture from the atmosphere and turns into a liquid`,
      `solid melts at 300K`,
    ],
    ans: "C",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: `A brand of ink containing cobalt(II), copper(II) and Iron(II) ions can best be separated into its various components by`,
    options: [
      `fractional crystallization`,
      `fractional distillation`,
      `sublimation`,
      `chromatography`,
    ],
    ans: "D",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: `Which of the following substances is a mixture?`,
    options: [
      `granulated sugar`,
      `sea-water`,
      `sodium chloride`,
      `iron fillings`,
    ],
    ans: "B",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: `Which of the following would support the conclusion that a solid sample is a mixture`,
    options: [
      `The solid can be ground to a fine powder`,
      `The density of the solid is 2.2 g/dm3`,
      `The solid has a melting range of 300 degree celcius to 375 degree celcius`,
      `The solid absorbs moisture from the atmosphere`,
    ],
    ans: "C",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: `Which of the following is a physical change?`,
    options: [
      `The bubbling of chlorine in a jar containing hydrogen`,
      `The bubbling of chlorine into water`,
      `The dissolution of sodium chlorine in water`,
      `The passing of steam over heated iron.`,
    ],
    ans: "C",
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: `Which of the following are mixture<br>I. Petroleum<br> II. Rubber<br>III. Vulcanizer's solution<br>IV. Carbon(II) Sulphide`,
    options: [
      `I, II, and III`,
      `I, II, and IV`,
      `I and II only`,
      `I and IV`,
    ],
    ans: "A",
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: `Which of the following can be obtained by fractional distillation?`,
    options: [
      `Nitrogen from liquid air.`,
      `Sodium chloride from sea water.`,
      `Iodine from a solution of iodine in carbon tetrachloride.`,
      `Sulfur from a solution of sulfur in carbon disulfide.`,
    ],
    ans: "A",
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: `Which of the following substances is not a homogenous mixture?`,
    options: [
      `Filtered sea water`,
      `Soft drink`,
      `Flood water`,
      `Writing Ink`,
    ],
    ans: "C",
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: `The dissolution of common salt in water is a physical change because`,
    options: [
      `the salt can be obtained by crystallization`,
      `the salt can be recovered by the evaporation of the water`,
      `heat is not generated during mixing`,
      `the solution will not boil at 100 deg celcius`,
    ],
    ans: "B",
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: `Which of the following substances is a mixture`,
    options: [
      `sulphur powder`,
      `bronze`,
      `distilled water`,
      `ethanol`,
    ],
    ans: "B",
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question: `A mixture of sand, ammonium chloride and sodium chloride is best separated by`,
    options: [
      `sublimation followed by addition of water and filtration`,
      `sublimation followed by addition of water and evaporation`,
      `addition of water followed by filtration and sublimation`,
      `addition of water followed by crystallization and sublimation`,
    ],
    ans: "B",
    // not yet answered
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: `A pure solid usually melts`,
    options: [
      `over a wide range of temperature`,
      `over a narrow range of temperature`,
      `at a lower temperature than the impure one`,
      `at the same temperature as the impure one`,
    ],
    ans: "A",
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: `Chromatography is used to separate components of mixtures which differs in their rates of`,
    options: [
      `diffusion`,
      `migration`,
      `reaction`,
      `sedimentation`,
    ],
    ans: "B",
  },
];
